<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ArcMenu</string>
    <string name="moon">The Moon is an astronomical body that orbits planet Earth, being Earths
        only permanent natural satellite. It is the fifth-largest natural satellite in the Solar
        System, and the largest among planetary satellites relative to the size of the planet that
        it orbits (its primary). Following Jupiters satellite Io, the Moon is second-densest satellite
        among those whose densities are known.
        The average distance of the Moon from the Earth is 384,400 km (238,900 mi),[10][11] or 1.28 light-seconds.
        The Moon is thought to have formed about 4.51 billion years ago, not long after Earth. There are several
        hypotheses for its origin; the most widely accepted explanation is that the Moon formed from the debris
        left over after a giant impact between Earth and a Mars-sized body called Theia.
        The Moon is in synchronous rotation with Earth, always showing the same face, with its near side marked
        by dark volcanic maria that fill the spaces between the bright ancient crustal highlands and the prominent
        impact craters. It is the second-brightest regularly visible celestial object in Earths sky, after the Sun,
        as measured by illuminance on Earths surface. Its surface is actually dark, although compared to the night
        sky it appears very bright, with a reflectance just slightly higher than that of worn asphalt. Its prominence
        in the sky and its regular cycle of phases have made the Moon an important cultural influence since ancient
        times on language, calendars, art, mythology, and, it is often speculated, the menstrual cycles of the female
        of the human species.[12]
        The Moons gravitational influence produces the ocean tides, body tides, and the slight lengthening of the day.
        The Moons current orbital distance is about thirty times the diameter of Earth, with its apparent size in the
        sky almost the same as that of the Sun, resulting in the Moon covering the Sun nearly precisely in total solar
        eclipse. This matching of apparent visual size will not continue in the far future. The Moons linear distance
        from Earth is currently increasing at a rate of 3.82 ± 0.07 centimetres (1.504 ± 0.028 in) per year, but this
        rate is not constant.
        The Soviet Unions Luna programme was the first to reach the Moon with uncrewed spacecraft in 1959; the United
        States NASA Apollo program achieved the only crewed missions to date, beginning with the first crewed lunar
        orbiting mission by Apollo 8 in 1968, and six crewed lunar landings between 1969 and 1972, with the first being
        Apollo 11. These missions returned over 380 kg (840 lb) of lunar rocks, which have been used to develop a
        geological understanding of the Moons origin, the formation of its internal structure, and its subsequent
        history. Since the Apollo 17 mission in 1972, the Moon has been visited only by uncrewed spacecraft.</string>
</resources>
